<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Photography on Tahir Hashmi</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/categories/photography/</link><description>Recent content in Photography on Tahir Hashmi</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-GB</language><managingEditor>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</managingEditor><webMaster>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 09:47:21 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tahirhashmi.com/categories/photography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fujifilm X-E4: An Engaging Experience I'd Rather Not Have</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/fujifilm-x-e4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 09:47:21 +0700</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/fujifilm-x-e4/</guid><description>When I&amp;rsquo;m on a business trip and I go for breakfast at the hotel&amp;rsquo;s restaurant, I want to take a few photos of the ambience and the food. However, my Nikon D750 feels a bit like an overkill for this job, as does my Nikon D500&amp;hellip; or Z6 or even Z50.
What I want for this occasion is something svelte. Like a Nikon Coolpix A or a Nikon J5. Except the former is as usable as a butter knife for carving steak and the latter is often outdone by an iPhone.</description></item><item><title>exiftool Examples</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2021/05/06/exiftool-examples/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 06:24:35 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2021/05/06/exiftool-examples/</guid><description>Following is a collection of real exiftool commands that I’ve used, along with explanations of what each does. exiftool is a command-line utility that provides very powerful EXIF reading, writing and searching capabilities.
I’m writing this down because I often spend a lot of time reading through exiftool documentation to find out how to get something done, just to forget it within hours. All of these examples work on a Unix shell environment like ZSH on MacOS or the various Linux shells.</description></item><item><title>D7100 and AF-P DX 70-300 VR on an Airshow</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2017/03/13/d7100-af-p-70-300-vr-airshow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 10:51:11 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2017/03/13/d7100-af-p-70-300-vr-airshow/</guid><description>Aero India is a biennial air show that takes place on an airfield on the outskirts of Bangalore. As per Wikipedia, it’s the world’s largest air show after the one in Paris. I first came to know of it when a friend of mine armed with a Nikon D70s and a non-VR 70-300 f/4-5.6 came back with some fabulous shots way back in 2007. Ten years later, I got to visit the show with a Nikon D7100 and an AF-P DX 70-300mm f/4.</description></item><item><title>Factoring the Crop</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2016/08/21/factoring-the-crop/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 04:57:18 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2016/08/21/factoring-the-crop/</guid><description>Here’s a picture whose EXIF I have stripped so you won’t know what equipment was used to shoot it.
If you had to guess the sensor size, considering that this is a minimally edited photo, what would be your guess? FX? DX? m43? 1″? 1/1.7″? 1/2.3″?
Small sensor systems are all the rage these days. 24-1200mm zoom in a handy little package. How about that? The problem is, tiny sensors come with compromises.</description></item><item><title>AF-S Nikkor 20mm ƒ/1.8G on DX</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2016/08/16/nikkor-20mm-on-dx/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 21:34:15 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2016/08/16/nikkor-20mm-on-dx/</guid><description>Early this year, I acquired a used 20mm ƒ/1.8G Nikkor lens. I only have DX bodies and the 20mm works more like a wide-normal prime than an ultra-wide, as on FX.
20mm ƒ/1.8G Nikkor on a D7100. It’s big. Why use 20mm ƒ/1.8G? on DX? I had long wanted to have a small, fast 24mm prime for my DX bodies. While the 35mm ƒ/1.8 DX is compact enough, I don’t like it that much.</description></item><item><title>Nikon D750 + 20mm f/1.8G Nikkor</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2015/03/24/nikon-d750-20mm-f1-8g-nikkor-tryout/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 12:25:11 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2015/03/24/nikon-d750-20mm-f1-8g-nikkor-tryout/</guid><description>A few days ago I got the opportunity to try out a Nikon D750, along with the new 20mm f/1.8G Nikkor lens. It wasn’t the best of times for trying out new toys for me, because of which I couldn’t get any presentable shots. I still got some shooting to do with it and I would go ahead to include those non-presentable shots anyway. Nikon D750 with 20mm f/1.8G Nikkor AF-S 20mm f/1.</description></item><item><title>Carrying Cameras</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2014/12/22/carrying-cameras/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2014 10:06:19 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2014/12/22/carrying-cameras/</guid><description>The Problem One of the big issues I face while photographing outdoors is that of having to carry a big 1.5 kg camera, and usually additional lenses and accessories weighing another 1-2 kg, all the time while out shooting for the day. The default carrying solution – neck strap – has a couple of disadvantages:
It’s extremely tiring for the neck muscles It’s very fiddly, and gets in the way too much Most of you might already have faced problem #1.</description></item><item><title>Sensor Format Blind Test Results</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/11/08/sensor-format-blind-test-results/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2013 11:57:06 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/11/08/sensor-format-blind-test-results/</guid><description>The results of the Sensor Format Blind Test are out!
I got a total of 13 responses, which is a bit too low for a full-blown, conclusive ranking analysis. We can, however, do some meaningful analysis if we ask simpler questions. To start with,
“Is the photo from Format X the best?”
To answer this question, we simply count the number of respondents who placed the photo from the given format as the best.</description></item><item><title>Sensor Format Blind Test</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/10/31/sensor-format-blind-test/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 11:41:11 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/10/31/sensor-format-blind-test/</guid><description>TL;DR Rank the four shots below from best to worst. Mention the position as top-right, bottom-left, etc. Submit your ranking as a comment. Rank the above images from best to worst. Mention positions as top-right, bottom-left, etc. The Fuss These are interesting times for camera enthusiasts. Digital cameras have advanced to a level where most cameras are capable of publication quality snaps and you don’t even need to carry a camera to take good pictures, thanks to smartphones.</description></item><item><title>Six Months with Nikon D7100</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/10/28/six-months-with-nikon-d7100/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2013 20:48:04 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/10/28/six-months-with-nikon-d7100/</guid><description>It’s been more than six months since I have had a Nikon D7100 for my own and I have been thinking of writing down my thoughts about the camera. However, these six months with the camera have been a bit of an up-and-down journey and it’s only now that I feel like I know the camera enough to write about it.
The D7100 is an enthusiasts’ camera and it will make you earn that title before you can be get along with it.</description></item><item><title>From Shooting RAWs to Shooting JPEGs</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/05/11/shooting-jpegs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 19:36:30 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/05/11/shooting-jpegs/</guid><description>To Shoot RAW or JPEG? I have been shooting photographs regularly for over 7 years now. I spent the first year shooting with a 2 Megapixel phone camera. Since then, however, I’ve almost always had RAW capable cameras and shot RAW compulsively. And why not? I get 16x or 64x more colour depth than JPEGs. I don’t have to bother about setting the right white balance, contrast or sharpness. I don’t have to choose between monochrome and colour at the time of shooting.</description></item><item><title>Nikon D90 vs. Sony RX100 in Goa</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/03/08/d90-vs-rx100-in-goa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 12:13:02 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/03/08/d90-vs-rx100-in-goa/</guid><description>Last weekend I was in Goa on a leisure trip, which gave me an excellent opportunity for some photography. I carried the RX100 for landscape and street photography. The D90 also came along mainly for long range shooting with the 55-300mm VR and low light shooting with the 50mm f/1.8D. This trip allowed me to sort out some things related to the pros and cons of using a big DSLR vs.</description></item><item><title>Nikon 1 J1 Review</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/02/25/nikon1-j1-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 13:09:45 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/02/25/nikon1-j1-review/</guid><description>My gear has evolved from P&amp;amp;S to DSLRs over the last five years, and each year I end up buying a new camera. The focus this year, was on reducing the size and weight of the camera gear, unlike previous years where I had been looking to acquire the latest sensor technology (although I was tempted to swap my D3100 with D3200!).
What started out as a quest for cheap backup P&amp;amp;S, ended up as a story about Nikon 1.</description></item><item><title>Impact of Sensor Size on Performance — a Contemporary Survey</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/02/09/sensor-size-vs-performance/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2013 12:41:10 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/02/09/sensor-size-vs-performance/</guid><description>I am in the middle of a choice between interchangeable lens systems and one of my pressing needs is the selection of a system that lets me have a smaller, lighter camera bag. Now is not a bad time to be shopping for cameras, with so much choice being available across price brackets and IQ variance. As always, having a lot to choose from is another way of getting confused, so I decided to do some objective data analysis to figure out what’s what.</description></item><item><title>State of the Camera 2012: Part 2</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/01/05/cameras-2012-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 22:03:29 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/01/05/cameras-2012-2/</guid><description>In Part 1 of this two-part series we looked at some of the dominant technology trends over the last couple of years and the impact they are having on cameras and photography. In this part of the series, I write about my impressions of a few recent cameras that I have had the opportunity to use.
Sony CyberShot DSC-RX100 Voted by Time Magazine as one of the best inventions of 2012 and declared to be the best pocket camera ever made by New York Times reviewer David Pogue, this camera has changed the way people respond to small sensor sizes.</description></item><item><title>State of the Camera 2012: Part 1</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2012/12/26/cameras-2012-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2012 20:16:25 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2012/12/26/cameras-2012-1/</guid><description>It’s been exactly two years since I last wrote about a camera on this blog. A lot has changed in the camera scene over the last two years and I fell in and out of love with the NEX-5 during this time as well. In this post I shall begin with talking about the recent trends in the camera market followed by short reviews of a few new generation cameras that I have tried or bought.</description></item><item><title>NEX-5 Early Impressions</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/12/26/nex-5-short-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2010 05:40:35 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/12/26/nex-5-short-review/</guid><description>It’s been a week since I’ve had my baby camera, i.e. the Sony α NEX-5 and I’ve been enjoying it so far. Here’s a quick low down of the ups and downs I’ve encountered with the camera.
The Good Outstanding IQ in any shooting conditions that can only be trumped by careful, deliberate shooting with a DSLR equipped with high quality optics Small enough to fit in my laptop bag, if not the jeans pocket Excellent iAuto mode for quick snapshots Fairly easy to use controls, esp.</description></item><item><title>My Imaging Tools and Workflow</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/11/01/software-toolkit-workflow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 14:15:50 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/11/01/software-toolkit-workflow/</guid><description>As my photos get backed up and burnt on to a DVD, I thought I might just do a quick cataloguing of the software I’ve found useful for developing my photographs and what each does. I’d also outline my workflow as I present each software in the order in which it appears in the workflow. Just to set the context, I use Microsoft Windows 7 for my imaging tasks, and my camera is a Nikon D90, so I do use a lot of Nikon software.</description></item><item><title>Which Compact Interchangeable-Lens Camera?</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/09/22/which-compact-camera/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2010 07:39:04 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/09/22/which-compact-camera/</guid><description>These are exciting times for DSLR enthusiasts. We’ve all marvelled at the creative and operational flexibility afforded by the large dial, switch and button infested DSLR bodies and interchangeable purpose-built lenses. We’ve been spoiled for the impeccable image quality afforded by the 8.5-15x larger APS-C sensors (upto 34x larger if you’re a 35mm shooter). It’s impossible to look back at compacts. Or is it?
Most DSLR shooters sooner or later realise that their beloved hunk can’t be their only camera.</description></item><item><title>Creating Hand-held HDRs</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/09/21/handheld-hdrs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2010 13:35:24 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/09/21/handheld-hdrs/</guid><description>On my recent vacation, I took a bunch of bracketed exposures to turn into HDRs. Before this trip I only used a tripod for bracketing. This time around, however, I had to deal with hand-held bracketed shots. To make things a bit worse, these shots included foliage, which isn’t always stationary between shots. Picturenaut utterly failed to align these images. I tried Luminance HDR (qtpfsgui) for Windows 7 (64-bit), and it simply kept crashing.</description></item><item><title>Capturing Rain</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/08/18/capturing-rain/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2010 03:58:32 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/08/18/capturing-rain/</guid><description>With the monsoons doing their usual thing and I having the luxury of a not-too-bad view of the rains, I had been itching to capture a shot of the rain in all its glory. Earlier this year I made a capture that brought out the rainy-ness in the scene but didn’t have any rain as such.
Online research about shooting the rains didn’t bring much enlightenment because there’s no “formula” for making rain shots.</description></item><item><title>Shooting in the Dark</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/08/03/shooting-in-the-dark/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 04:21:30 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/08/03/shooting-in-the-dark/</guid><description>Digital sensors have made a lot of progress on the light efficiency front. The Nikon D3s sensor, currently the most efficient sensor available, offers amazingly clean images at crazy high ISOs. Something that film shooters could only dream of. There is still some time, however, before a D3s calibre sensor makes it to consumer bodies. Meanwhile, it will help knowing the tips and tricks of shooting in the dark for the win.</description></item></channel></rss>