<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reviews on Tahir Hashmi</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/categories/reviews/</link><description>Recent content in Reviews on Tahir Hashmi</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-GB</language><managingEditor>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</managingEditor><webMaster>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 18:25:48 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tahirhashmi.com/categories/reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fujifilm X100V Review: An Unfulfilled Dream</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/x100v-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 18:25:48 +0700</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/x100v-review/</guid><description>Fujifilm X100V Review: An Unfulfilled Dream A few months ago, I reviewed the Fujifilm X-E4 and mentioned that I got that camera because
For years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been searching for something that&amp;rsquo;s compact, elegant and competent &amp;ndash; a &amp;ldquo;Vanity Camera&amp;rdquo;, as I call it. After much deliberation, I settled on getting the world&amp;rsquo;s prettiest camera, a Fujifilm x100v. Except, as of this writing, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a new body in three different countries that I looked.</description></item><item><title>Fujifilm X-E4: An Engaging Experience I'd Rather Not Have</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/fujifilm-x-e4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 09:47:21 +0700</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/fujifilm-x-e4/</guid><description>When I&amp;rsquo;m on a business trip and I go for breakfast at the hotel&amp;rsquo;s restaurant, I want to take a few photos of the ambience and the food. However, my Nikon D750 feels a bit like an overkill for this job, as does my Nikon D500&amp;hellip; or Z6 or even Z50.
What I want for this occasion is something svelte. Like a Nikon Coolpix A or a Nikon J5. Except the former is as usable as a butter knife for carving steak and the latter is often outdone by an iPhone.</description></item><item><title>D7100 and AF-P DX 70-300 VR on an Airshow</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2017/03/13/d7100-af-p-70-300-vr-airshow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 10:51:11 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2017/03/13/d7100-af-p-70-300-vr-airshow/</guid><description>Aero India is a biennial air show that takes place on an airfield on the outskirts of Bangalore. As per Wikipedia, it’s the world’s largest air show after the one in Paris. I first came to know of it when a friend of mine armed with a Nikon D70s and a non-VR 70-300 f/4-5.6 came back with some fabulous shots way back in 2007. Ten years later, I got to visit the show with a Nikon D7100 and an AF-P DX 70-300mm f/4.</description></item><item><title>AF-S Nikkor 20mm ƒ/1.8G on DX</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2016/08/16/nikkor-20mm-on-dx/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 21:34:15 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2016/08/16/nikkor-20mm-on-dx/</guid><description>Early this year, I acquired a used 20mm ƒ/1.8G Nikkor lens. I only have DX bodies and the 20mm works more like a wide-normal prime than an ultra-wide, as on FX.
20mm ƒ/1.8G Nikkor on a D7100. It’s big. Why use 20mm ƒ/1.8G? on DX? I had long wanted to have a small, fast 24mm prime for my DX bodies. While the 35mm ƒ/1.8 DX is compact enough, I don’t like it that much.</description></item><item><title>Nikon D750 + 20mm f/1.8G Nikkor</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2015/03/24/nikon-d750-20mm-f1-8g-nikkor-tryout/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 12:25:11 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2015/03/24/nikon-d750-20mm-f1-8g-nikkor-tryout/</guid><description>A few days ago I got the opportunity to try out a Nikon D750, along with the new 20mm f/1.8G Nikkor lens. It wasn’t the best of times for trying out new toys for me, because of which I couldn’t get any presentable shots. I still got some shooting to do with it and I would go ahead to include those non-presentable shots anyway. Nikon D750 with 20mm f/1.8G Nikkor AF-S 20mm f/1.</description></item><item><title>Six Months with Nikon D7100</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/10/28/six-months-with-nikon-d7100/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2013 20:48:04 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/10/28/six-months-with-nikon-d7100/</guid><description>It’s been more than six months since I have had a Nikon D7100 for my own and I have been thinking of writing down my thoughts about the camera. However, these six months with the camera have been a bit of an up-and-down journey and it’s only now that I feel like I know the camera enough to write about it.
The D7100 is an enthusiasts’ camera and it will make you earn that title before you can be get along with it.</description></item><item><title>Nikon D90 vs. Sony RX100 in Goa</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/03/08/d90-vs-rx100-in-goa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 12:13:02 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/03/08/d90-vs-rx100-in-goa/</guid><description>Last weekend I was in Goa on a leisure trip, which gave me an excellent opportunity for some photography. I carried the RX100 for landscape and street photography. The D90 also came along mainly for long range shooting with the 55-300mm VR and low light shooting with the 50mm f/1.8D. This trip allowed me to sort out some things related to the pros and cons of using a big DSLR vs.</description></item><item><title>Nikon 1 J1 Review</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/02/25/nikon1-j1-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 13:09:45 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/02/25/nikon1-j1-review/</guid><description>My gear has evolved from P&amp;amp;S to DSLRs over the last five years, and each year I end up buying a new camera. The focus this year, was on reducing the size and weight of the camera gear, unlike previous years where I had been looking to acquire the latest sensor technology (although I was tempted to swap my D3100 with D3200!).
What started out as a quest for cheap backup P&amp;amp;S, ended up as a story about Nikon 1.</description></item><item><title>NEX-5 Early Impressions</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/12/26/nex-5-short-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2010 05:40:35 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/12/26/nex-5-short-review/</guid><description>It’s been a week since I’ve had my baby camera, i.e. the Sony α NEX-5 and I’ve been enjoying it so far. Here’s a quick low down of the ups and downs I’ve encountered with the camera.
The Good Outstanding IQ in any shooting conditions that can only be trumped by careful, deliberate shooting with a DSLR equipped with high quality optics Small enough to fit in my laptop bag, if not the jeans pocket Excellent iAuto mode for quick snapshots Fairly easy to use controls, esp.</description></item></channel></rss>