<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>programming on Tahir Hashmi</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/tags/programming/</link><description>Recent content in programming on Tahir Hashmi</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-GB</language><managingEditor>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</managingEditor><webMaster>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 10:12:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tahirhashmi.com/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Best Feature of Go</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2018/06/01/best-feature-of-go/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 10:12:41 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2018/06/01/best-feature-of-go/</guid><description>I’ve been programming since the late 90’s and I’ve done quite a bit of coding in C, C++, a lot of it in PHP and some in Python as well. On the front-end I’ve done some JavaScript and I’ve also had the misfortune of programming in Java 😉
I started programming in Go in 2012 and since then I haven’t wanted to program in any other language. I’ve had a handful of large Go implementations across two companies and by now I have my own short list of favourite features.</description></item><item><title>Inheritance Semantics in Go</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2014/01/22/inheritance-semantics-in-go/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 11:16:12 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2014/01/22/inheritance-semantics-in-go/</guid><description>Contemporary application design discipline is deeply rooted in Object Oriented Analysis and Design and inheritance is a key concept in OOAD. Go does not support classes and inheritance in their classic OOP sense but since many of us are trained in OOP, the loss of an important design concept sometimes feels restrictive.
Even though I knew about embedding and interfaces, their connection with classic inheritance wasn’t quite obvious. I set out to understand how I could emulate the coarse inheritance semantics in Go, without going into fine nuances.</description></item><item><title>Why I Program in Go</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/01/05/why-program-in-go/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2013 11:06:00 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/01/05/why-program-in-go/</guid><description>Go is a fresh new programming language, that has come out of Google and is primarily targeted towards server development. It is developed by some very accomplished computer scientists, like Ken Thompson and Rob Pike. I recently launched a significant new product built with Go at work, and it has proved itself out very well in terms of developer productivity and performance. So much so that many other teams are also giving it a go (oh, how punny this language’s name is).</description></item><item><title>MySQLdb Leaks Memory</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/06/30/mysqldb-leaks-memory/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2010 11:32:30 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/06/30/mysqldb-leaks-memory/</guid><description>Whenever people search for a Python library for MySQL, they get directed to MySQL for Python. However, there are some nasties hidden in it. Searching for “mysql python memory leaks” results in a few links which suggest that using Unicode causes memory leaks with the library.
Today, however, I found another cause for MySQLdb memory leaks, while debugging a leaky Python daemon at work — database errors.
Use this script:</description></item></channel></rss>