<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Articles about Software, Photography and more on Tahir Hashmi</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Articles about Software, Photography and more on Tahir Hashmi</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-GB</language><managingEditor>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</managingEditor><webMaster>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</webMaster><atom:link href="https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fujifilm X-E4: An Engaging Experience I'd Rather Not Have</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/fujifilm-x-e4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 09:47:21 +0700</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/fujifilm-x-e4/</guid><description>When I&amp;rsquo;m on a business trip and I go for breakfast at the hotel&amp;rsquo;s restaurant, I want to take a few photos of the ambience and the food. However, my Nikon D750 feels a bit like an overkill for this job, as does my Nikon D500&amp;hellip; or Z6 or even Z50.
What I want for this occasion is something svelte. Like a Nikon Coolpix A or a Nikon J5. Except the former is as usable as a butter knife for carving steak and the latter is often outdone by an iPhone.</description></item><item><title>exiftool Examples</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2021/05/06/exiftool-examples/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 06:24:35 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2021/05/06/exiftool-examples/</guid><description>Following is a collection of real exiftool commands that I’ve used, along with explanations of what each does. exiftool is a command-line utility that provides very powerful EXIF reading, writing and searching capabilities.
I’m writing this down because I often spend a lot of time reading through exiftool documentation to find out how to get something done, just to forget it within hours. All of these examples work on a Unix shell environment like ZSH on MacOS or the various Linux shells.</description></item><item><title>Using a QLC SSD for Backups. Am I Insane?</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2020/09/10/using-a-qlc-ssd-for-backups-makes-sense/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 15:06:37 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2020/09/10/using-a-qlc-ssd-for-backups-makes-sense/</guid><description>I have a properly working Seagate Backup Plus Hub. However, I’m now using a Samsung 870 QVO for Time Machine backups on my Mac, despite its bottom-of-the-pile TBW (durability) rating. It actually makes sense.
The Backstory I have a 2017 iMac (bought that year as well) which I use as my primary home computer for photo/video editing, a bit of programming and a lot of Netflix and HBO Go as well.</description></item><item><title>Buy or Build?</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2020/04/18/buy-or-build/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 06:58:04 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2020/04/18/buy-or-build/</guid><description>One of the decisions a CTO has to frequently make is whether to build some piece of functionality in-house or buy it from a third party vendor. In this post, I share my framework for making these decisions.
I also include a case study each for a buy decision and a build decision. Added bonus – some thoughts on whether you should sell something you’ve decided to build.
Functional Complexity One of the most important determinants of buy-vs-build decisions will be the ability to spec out the entire functionality.</description></item><item><title>5 Competitive Advantages in Technology</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2019/01/19/5-competitive-advantages-in-technology/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 07:47:52 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2019/01/19/5-competitive-advantages-in-technology/</guid><description>The technology universe is in a constant state of flux with new advancements arriving faster than one could keep up. A technology leader, in this scenario, needs to look for something durable to build the foundation of their new (or improved) technology organisation.
Spending 36 months leading the charge (and occasionally failing) at a fast growing business that’s powered by technology can teach a lot. Coming off the back of a career built with customer-facing development teams at companies serving over 100 million customers, I now have some idea of what it takes to make a strong technology foundation for a modern business.</description></item><item><title>The Best Feature of Go</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2018/06/01/best-feature-of-go/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 10:12:41 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2018/06/01/best-feature-of-go/</guid><description>I’ve been programming since the late 90’s and I’ve done quite a bit of coding in C, C++, a lot of it in PHP and some in Python as well. On the front-end I’ve done some JavaScript and I’ve also had the misfortune of programming in Java 😉
I started programming in Go in 2012 and since then I haven’t wanted to program in any other language. I’ve had a handful of large Go implementations across two companies and by now I have my own short list of favourite features.</description></item><item><title>D7100 and AF-P DX 70-300 VR on an Airshow</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2017/03/13/d7100-af-p-70-300-vr-airshow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 10:51:11 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2017/03/13/d7100-af-p-70-300-vr-airshow/</guid><description>Aero India is a biennial air show that takes place on an airfield on the outskirts of Bangalore. As per Wikipedia, it’s the world’s largest air show after the one in Paris. I first came to know of it when a friend of mine armed with a Nikon D70s and a non-VR 70-300 f/4-5.6 came back with some fabulous shots way back in 2007. Ten years later, I got to visit the show with a Nikon D7100 and an AF-P DX 70-300mm f/4.</description></item><item><title>Factoring the Crop</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2016/08/21/factoring-the-crop/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 04:57:18 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2016/08/21/factoring-the-crop/</guid><description>Here’s a picture whose EXIF I have stripped so you won’t know what equipment was used to shoot it.
If you had to guess the sensor size, considering that this is a minimally edited photo, what would be your guess? FX? DX? m43? 1″? 1/1.7″? 1/2.3″?
Small sensor systems are all the rage these days. 24-1200mm zoom in a handy little package. How about that? The problem is, tiny sensors come with compromises.</description></item><item><title>AF-S Nikkor 20mm ƒ/1.8G on DX</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2016/08/16/nikkor-20mm-on-dx/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 21:34:15 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2016/08/16/nikkor-20mm-on-dx/</guid><description>Early this year, I acquired a used 20mm ƒ/1.8G Nikkor lens. I only have DX bodies and the 20mm works more like a wide-normal prime than an ultra-wide, as on FX.
20mm ƒ/1.8G Nikkor on a D7100. It’s big. Why use 20mm ƒ/1.8G? on DX? I had long wanted to have a small, fast 24mm prime for my DX bodies. While the 35mm ƒ/1.8 DX is compact enough, I don’t like it that much.</description></item><item><title>Nikon D750 + 20mm f/1.8G Nikkor</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2015/03/24/nikon-d750-20mm-f1-8g-nikkor-tryout/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 12:25:11 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2015/03/24/nikon-d750-20mm-f1-8g-nikkor-tryout/</guid><description>A few days ago I got the opportunity to try out a Nikon D750, along with the new 20mm f/1.8G Nikkor lens. It wasn’t the best of times for trying out new toys for me, because of which I couldn’t get any presentable shots. I still got some shooting to do with it and I would go ahead to include those non-presentable shots anyway. Nikon D750 with 20mm f/1.8G Nikkor AF-S 20mm f/1.</description></item><item><title>Carrying Cameras</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2014/12/22/carrying-cameras/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2014 10:06:19 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2014/12/22/carrying-cameras/</guid><description>The Problem One of the big issues I face while photographing outdoors is that of having to carry a big 1.5 kg camera, and usually additional lenses and accessories weighing another 1-2 kg, all the time while out shooting for the day. The default carrying solution – neck strap – has a couple of disadvantages:
It’s extremely tiring for the neck muscles It’s very fiddly, and gets in the way too much Most of you might already have faced problem #1.</description></item><item><title>Farewell, Photography</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2014/05/20/farewell-photography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 19:01:20 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2014/05/20/farewell-photography/</guid><description>Update: I couldn’t stay away for long. That, and I conquered the sharpness gremlins plaguing my experience with the heavily used AF-S DX 16-85mm f/3.5-5.6G VR.
We had a good thing going for eight years or so, but it’s time now to bring it to a halt.
Back when I started, I had no dearth of time to give to myself and I had no one but myself to spend money on.</description></item><item><title>Inheritance Semantics in Go</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2014/01/22/inheritance-semantics-in-go/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 11:16:12 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2014/01/22/inheritance-semantics-in-go/</guid><description>Contemporary application design discipline is deeply rooted in Object Oriented Analysis and Design and inheritance is a key concept in OOAD. Go does not support classes and inheritance in their classic OOP sense but since many of us are trained in OOP, the loss of an important design concept sometimes feels restrictive.
Even though I knew about embedding and interfaces, their connection with classic inheritance wasn’t quite obvious. I set out to understand how I could emulate the coarse inheritance semantics in Go, without going into fine nuances.</description></item><item><title>Sensor Format Blind Test Results</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/11/08/sensor-format-blind-test-results/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2013 11:57:06 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/11/08/sensor-format-blind-test-results/</guid><description>The results of the Sensor Format Blind Test are out!
I got a total of 13 responses, which is a bit too low for a full-blown, conclusive ranking analysis. We can, however, do some meaningful analysis if we ask simpler questions. To start with,
“Is the photo from Format X the best?”
To answer this question, we simply count the number of respondents who placed the photo from the given format as the best.</description></item><item><title>Sensor Format Blind Test</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/10/31/sensor-format-blind-test/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 11:41:11 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/10/31/sensor-format-blind-test/</guid><description>TL;DR Rank the four shots below from best to worst. Mention the position as top-right, bottom-left, etc. Submit your ranking as a comment. Rank the above images from best to worst. Mention positions as top-right, bottom-left, etc. The Fuss These are interesting times for camera enthusiasts. Digital cameras have advanced to a level where most cameras are capable of publication quality snaps and you don’t even need to carry a camera to take good pictures, thanks to smartphones.</description></item><item><title>Mapping OO Interfaces to REST</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/10/28/mapping-oo-interfaces-to-rest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 09:35:46 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/10/28/mapping-oo-interfaces-to-rest/</guid><description>A few days ago, my BBF (Big Boss Forever) Vijay R asked the following question:
Any resources on how to map OO design (controlled state change via methods) to RESTful services? #help
— Vijay Ramachandran (@vijay750) October 24, 2013
Here’s what I think about it. There are a few things that are very different about designing HTTP APIs as compared to language-native implementation design:
The goal of an HTTP API is to minimise coupling and facilitate interoperability, which is less of a concern when the usage environment is restricted to a single programming language and its runtime</description></item><item><title>Six Months with Nikon D7100</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/10/28/six-months-with-nikon-d7100/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2013 20:48:04 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/10/28/six-months-with-nikon-d7100/</guid><description>It’s been more than six months since I have had a Nikon D7100 for my own and I have been thinking of writing down my thoughts about the camera. However, these six months with the camera have been a bit of an up-and-down journey and it’s only now that I feel like I know the camera enough to write about it.
The D7100 is an enthusiasts’ camera and it will make you earn that title before you can be get along with it.</description></item><item><title>The Lost Flickr of Hope</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/07/04/the-lost-flickr-of-hope/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 10:35:39 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/07/04/the-lost-flickr-of-hope/</guid><description>I woke up this Tuesday morning to a shock.
OMG this Yahoo! bar on top of @Flickr is fugly. If this bar doesn’t go from Flickr, I will. pic.twitter.com/dolGKR8jJu
— Tahir (@codie) July 2, 2013
This bar is wrong in a lot of ways. The way it stands out in all its ugliness from the rest of the Flickr visual design speaks volumes about how it was executed (thoughtlessly, in a draconian way), how little the Flickr development team have a say in how things work (I can’t imagine a product owner who would allow such visual desecration of their product without a protest) and how little Yahoo!</description></item><item><title>From Shooting RAWs to Shooting JPEGs</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/05/11/shooting-jpegs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 19:36:30 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/05/11/shooting-jpegs/</guid><description>To Shoot RAW or JPEG? I have been shooting photographs regularly for over 7 years now. I spent the first year shooting with a 2 Megapixel phone camera. Since then, however, I’ve almost always had RAW capable cameras and shot RAW compulsively. And why not? I get 16x or 64x more colour depth than JPEGs. I don’t have to bother about setting the right white balance, contrast or sharpness. I don’t have to choose between monochrome and colour at the time of shooting.</description></item><item><title>Nikon D90 vs. Sony RX100 in Goa</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/03/08/d90-vs-rx100-in-goa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 12:13:02 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/03/08/d90-vs-rx100-in-goa/</guid><description>Last weekend I was in Goa on a leisure trip, which gave me an excellent opportunity for some photography. I carried the RX100 for landscape and street photography. The D90 also came along mainly for long range shooting with the 55-300mm VR and low light shooting with the 50mm f/1.8D. This trip allowed me to sort out some things related to the pros and cons of using a big DSLR vs.</description></item><item><title>Nikon 1 J1 Review</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/02/25/nikon1-j1-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 13:09:45 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/02/25/nikon1-j1-review/</guid><description>My gear has evolved from P&amp;amp;S to DSLRs over the last five years, and each year I end up buying a new camera. The focus this year, was on reducing the size and weight of the camera gear, unlike previous years where I had been looking to acquire the latest sensor technology (although I was tempted to swap my D3100 with D3200!).
What started out as a quest for cheap backup P&amp;amp;S, ended up as a story about Nikon 1.</description></item><item><title>Impact of Sensor Size on Performance — a Contemporary Survey</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/02/09/sensor-size-vs-performance/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2013 12:41:10 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/02/09/sensor-size-vs-performance/</guid><description>I am in the middle of a choice between interchangeable lens systems and one of my pressing needs is the selection of a system that lets me have a smaller, lighter camera bag. Now is not a bad time to be shopping for cameras, with so much choice being available across price brackets and IQ variance. As always, having a lot to choose from is another way of getting confused, so I decided to do some objective data analysis to figure out what’s what.</description></item><item><title>The Compiler as a Refactoring Aid</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/01/23/the-compiler-as-a-refactoring-aid/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 14:15:14 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/01/23/the-compiler-as-a-refactoring-aid/</guid><description>Recently, I sat down to refactor a Go application with a high-level design objective in place. The application had two conceptually separate entities implemented in different files but mashed into a single package. I needed to separate them out into their own packages. I wasn’t using an IDE — just Emacs with basic formatting and non-contextual auto-complete aids.
I started out by creating a new directory for the package to be split out and moved the files that contained most of the relevant code into that directory, without thinking of the consequences.</description></item><item><title>Go Workshop</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/01/21/go-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 11:56:29 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/01/21/go-workshop/</guid><description>Last week, I conducted a 2 day Go Workshop at my workplace. It was fun.
I started day 1 with the excellent Go at Google presentation by Rob Pike, followed by my own presentation of Go’s key features. The rest of Day 1 was spent taking the Go Tour.
The coolest thing I did was on day 2. I mirrored my laptop on the projector and went through a fresh install of Go from source on my [newly allocated] dev box.</description></item><item><title>Why I Program in Go</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/01/05/why-program-in-go/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2013 11:06:00 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/01/05/why-program-in-go/</guid><description>Go is a fresh new programming language, that has come out of Google and is primarily targeted towards server development. It is developed by some very accomplished computer scientists, like Ken Thompson and Rob Pike. I recently launched a significant new product built with Go at work, and it has proved itself out very well in terms of developer productivity and performance. So much so that many other teams are also giving it a go (oh, how punny this language’s name is).</description></item><item><title>State of the Camera 2012: Part 2</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/01/05/cameras-2012-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 22:03:29 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/01/05/cameras-2012-2/</guid><description>In Part 1 of this two-part series we looked at some of the dominant technology trends over the last couple of years and the impact they are having on cameras and photography. In this part of the series, I write about my impressions of a few recent cameras that I have had the opportunity to use.
Sony CyberShot DSC-RX100 Voted by Time Magazine as one of the best inventions of 2012 and declared to be the best pocket camera ever made by New York Times reviewer David Pogue, this camera has changed the way people respond to small sensor sizes.</description></item><item><title>State of the Camera 2012: Part 1</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2012/12/26/cameras-2012-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2012 20:16:25 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2012/12/26/cameras-2012-1/</guid><description>It’s been exactly two years since I last wrote about a camera on this blog. A lot has changed in the camera scene over the last two years and I fell in and out of love with the NEX-5 during this time as well. In this post I shall begin with talking about the recent trends in the camera market followed by short reviews of a few new generation cameras that I have tried or bought.</description></item><item><title>High on Lo-Fi</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2012/02/15/high-on-lo-fi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2012 14:12:36 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2012/02/15/high-on-lo-fi/</guid><description>The camera industry is going through some pretty big movements these days. Since the advent of digital cameras and social networking websites, more and more people have been finding interest in taking photos and exhibiting them online to friends and public at large. Somewhere in this explosive growth of photography, veterans and early enthusiasts sometimes find themselves in a tight spot.
Big Camera, Small Camera Since their inception, digital camera sensors have been pushing the boundaries of the quality of images they produce.</description></item><item><title>Find and Edit File</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2011/11/24/find-and-edit-file/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2011 10:28:09 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2011/11/24/find-and-edit-file/</guid><description>While working on a huge code-base with several thousand source files, it becomes difficult to remember where each file is. If you use conventions like one file per class, you can at least figure out the file name. E.g. the definition of class Foo would be found in Foo.class.xx or something like that.
Thankfully, ack makes it easy to find the location files in a project. Just say, ack -g Foo.</description></item><item><title>Need a new Start-up Idea? Mash up Social and Cloud</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2011/09/19/new-start-up-idea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2011 10:19:55 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2011/09/19/new-start-up-idea/</guid><description>Are you based out of India and need an idea for a technology start-up? Try thinking of two of the biggest technology buzzwords of the day and mash ’em up together. Social + Cloud!
Back in the ol’ days when system programming and desktop applications were hot, people were trying to create applications that could run on more than one OS. There was a sprouting of libraries, proprietary and open source, that promised abstraction from the operating system internals.</description></item><item><title>NEX-5 Early Impressions</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/12/26/nex-5-short-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2010 05:40:35 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/12/26/nex-5-short-review/</guid><description>It’s been a week since I’ve had my baby camera, i.e. the Sony α NEX-5 and I’ve been enjoying it so far. Here’s a quick low down of the ups and downs I’ve encountered with the camera.
The Good Outstanding IQ in any shooting conditions that can only be trumped by careful, deliberate shooting with a DSLR equipped with high quality optics Small enough to fit in my laptop bag, if not the jeans pocket Excellent iAuto mode for quick snapshots Fairly easy to use controls, esp.</description></item><item><title>My Imaging Tools and Workflow</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/11/01/software-toolkit-workflow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 14:15:50 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/11/01/software-toolkit-workflow/</guid><description>As my photos get backed up and burnt on to a DVD, I thought I might just do a quick cataloguing of the software I’ve found useful for developing my photographs and what each does. I’d also outline my workflow as I present each software in the order in which it appears in the workflow. Just to set the context, I use Microsoft Windows 7 for my imaging tasks, and my camera is a Nikon D90, so I do use a lot of Nikon software.</description></item><item><title>Which Compact Interchangeable-Lens Camera?</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/09/22/which-compact-camera/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2010 07:39:04 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/09/22/which-compact-camera/</guid><description>These are exciting times for DSLR enthusiasts. We’ve all marvelled at the creative and operational flexibility afforded by the large dial, switch and button infested DSLR bodies and interchangeable purpose-built lenses. We’ve been spoiled for the impeccable image quality afforded by the 8.5-15x larger APS-C sensors (upto 34x larger if you’re a 35mm shooter). It’s impossible to look back at compacts. Or is it?
Most DSLR shooters sooner or later realise that their beloved hunk can’t be their only camera.</description></item><item><title>Creating Hand-held HDRs</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/09/21/handheld-hdrs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2010 13:35:24 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/09/21/handheld-hdrs/</guid><description>On my recent vacation, I took a bunch of bracketed exposures to turn into HDRs. Before this trip I only used a tripod for bracketing. This time around, however, I had to deal with hand-held bracketed shots. To make things a bit worse, these shots included foliage, which isn’t always stationary between shots. Picturenaut utterly failed to align these images. I tried Luminance HDR (qtpfsgui) for Windows 7 (64-bit), and it simply kept crashing.</description></item><item><title>Beating the TripAdvisor Badge’s SEO Tactic</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/08/24/beating-tripadvisor-seo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2010 10:16:38 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/08/24/beating-tripadvisor-seo/</guid><description>The Problem Recently, I got a reference to this article from my Product Manager, regarding TripAdvisor badges and how they boost SEO. Their secret is a simple link that links deep into TripAdvisor website and makes your site a donor of link love to TripAdvisor. This is somewhat bad for hotel owners who might find that TripAdvisor trumps the search ranking for their brand name.
The easy solution to prevent that from happening would be to slightly edit TA widget and use a rel=&amp;quot;nofollow&amp;quot; attribute in the anchor that links to TripAdvisor.</description></item><item><title>Capturing Rain</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/08/18/capturing-rain/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2010 03:58:32 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/08/18/capturing-rain/</guid><description>With the monsoons doing their usual thing and I having the luxury of a not-too-bad view of the rains, I had been itching to capture a shot of the rain in all its glory. Earlier this year I made a capture that brought out the rainy-ness in the scene but didn’t have any rain as such.
Online research about shooting the rains didn’t bring much enlightenment because there’s no “formula” for making rain shots.</description></item><item><title>Simple PHP Timer</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/08/09/simple-php-timer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2010 12:23:45 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/08/09/simple-php-timer/</guid><description>I was just trying to profile an HTML page for performance bottle-necks. I’m trying to follow a top-down approach, wherein I start from the entry script, and find the block of code that takes the biggest chunk of time before digging deeper into that chunk.
At this stage, it’s not feasible to drop in a full-blown profiling tool like xdebug because of the set-up overhead and amount of data it generates.</description></item><item><title>Shooting in the Dark</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/08/03/shooting-in-the-dark/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 04:21:30 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/08/03/shooting-in-the-dark/</guid><description>Digital sensors have made a lot of progress on the light efficiency front. The Nikon D3s sensor, currently the most efficient sensor available, offers amazingly clean images at crazy high ISOs. Something that film shooters could only dream of. There is still some time, however, before a D3s calibre sensor makes it to consumer bodies. Meanwhile, it will help knowing the tips and tricks of shooting in the dark for the win.</description></item><item><title>Take Two</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/07/31/hello-world-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2010 11:55:35 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/07/31/hello-world-2/</guid><description>This isn’t my first time writing a photography blog. I started one, almost 3 years ago and wrote a few posts regarding technique and gear. It was probably too early to start writing, though, and the blog fell off the edge when my hosting plan expired and I didn’t renew it. This time, it will hopefully stay.
Photography is, for me, a new way to experience things. It’s about delving deep into the visual characteristics of the environment around me — shapes, contours, colours, location, the light that I’m seeing by.</description></item><item><title>PHP vs. Python for Web Apps</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/07/28/php-vs-python-for-web-apps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2010 12:00:42 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/07/28/php-vs-python-for-web-apps/</guid><description>These days, more and more people ask the Python vs. PHP question when they start out with a web application from scratch. I’ve developed PHP applications for 5 years but for the last couple of years I’ve been doing Python. This post is meant to note some of my observations. If you don’t want to read the whole of it, my opinion — opinion — is to stick with PHP for dishing out your *ML.</description></item><item><title>MySQLdb Leaks Memory</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/06/30/mysqldb-leaks-memory/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2010 11:32:30 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/06/30/mysqldb-leaks-memory/</guid><description>Whenever people search for a Python library for MySQL, they get directed to MySQL for Python. However, there are some nasties hidden in it. Searching for “mysql python memory leaks” results in a few links which suggest that using Unicode causes memory leaks with the library.
Today, however, I found another cause for MySQLdb memory leaks, while debugging a leaky Python daemon at work — database errors.
Use this script:</description></item><item><title>{Browse ‘Hello World!’}</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/06/18/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2010 15:21:35 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/06/18/hello-world/</guid><description>That snippet of Oz somehow felt like an appropriate title for the first post on my tech blog. Expect something new here once in a while. Happy hacking! 🙂</description></item></channel></rss>