<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mirrorless on Tahir Hashmi</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/tags/mirrorless/</link><description>Recent content in mirrorless on Tahir Hashmi</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-GB</language><managingEditor>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</managingEditor><webMaster>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 22:03:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tahirhashmi.com/tags/mirrorless/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>State of the Camera 2012: Part 2</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/01/05/cameras-2012-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 22:03:29 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2013/01/05/cameras-2012-2/</guid><description>In Part 1 of this two-part series we looked at some of the dominant technology trends over the last couple of years and the impact they are having on cameras and photography. In this part of the series, I write about my impressions of a few recent cameras that I have had the opportunity to use.
Sony CyberShot DSC-RX100 Voted by Time Magazine as one of the best inventions of 2012 and declared to be the best pocket camera ever made by New York Times reviewer David Pogue, this camera has changed the way people respond to small sensor sizes.</description></item><item><title>State of the Camera 2012: Part 1</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2012/12/26/cameras-2012-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2012 20:16:25 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2012/12/26/cameras-2012-1/</guid><description>It’s been exactly two years since I last wrote about a camera on this blog. A lot has changed in the camera scene over the last two years and I fell in and out of love with the NEX-5 during this time as well. In this post I shall begin with talking about the recent trends in the camera market followed by short reviews of a few new generation cameras that I have tried or bought.</description></item><item><title>Which Compact Interchangeable-Lens Camera?</title><link>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/09/22/which-compact-camera/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2010 07:39:04 +0000</pubDate><author>mail@tahirhashmi.com (Tahir Hashmi)</author><guid>https://tahirhashmi.com/posts/2010/09/22/which-compact-camera/</guid><description>These are exciting times for DSLR enthusiasts. We’ve all marvelled at the creative and operational flexibility afforded by the large dial, switch and button infested DSLR bodies and interchangeable purpose-built lenses. We’ve been spoiled for the impeccable image quality afforded by the 8.5-15x larger APS-C sensors (upto 34x larger if you’re a 35mm shooter). It’s impossible to look back at compacts. Or is it?
Most DSLR shooters sooner or later realise that their beloved hunk can’t be their only camera.</description></item></channel></rss>